<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL Community on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/sql-community/</link><description>Recent content in SQL Community on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/sql-community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2016 - That was a Year :-)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/2016-that-was-a-year-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/2016-that-was-a-year-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Its the time of year for reflection and I have had the most amazing 2016, I am blessed that I love what I do so much. I thoroughly enjoy writing and talking and sharing and commenting and supporting and cherishing all the SQL and PowerShell things. &lt;a class="link" href="http://sqldbawithabeard.com/2016/10/29/powerbi-and-api-visualising-my-checkins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;I wrote about using Power Bi to display my checkins&lt;/a&gt;. I only started this in June and this is where I have been :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell CMDLets added for SQL2016 Always Encrypted</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershell-cmdlets-added-for-sql2016-always-encrypted/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershell-cmdlets-added-for-sql2016-always-encrypted/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://blogs.technet.microsoft.com/dataplatforminsider/2016/06/30/sql-PowerShell-july-2016-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;The post on the SQLServer blog at TechNet by the SQL Server Tools Team today&lt;/a&gt; made me jump out of my seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The July update for SSMS includes the first substantial improvement in SQL PowerShell in many years. We owe a lot of thanks for this effort to the great collaboration with our community. We have several new CMDLETs to share with you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one release there are &lt;strong&gt;twenty-five&lt;/strong&gt; new CMDLets for the new sqlserver module&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShelling SQL Saturday Sessions to the Guidebook app</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershelling-sql-saturday-sessions-to-the-guidebook-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershelling-sql-saturday-sessions-to-the-guidebook-app/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from my &lt;a class="link" href="http://sqldbawithabeard.com/2015/03/21/parsing-xml-child-nodes-and-converting-to-datetime-with-PowerShell/" title="Parsing XML Child Nodes and Converting to DateTime with PowerShell"
target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;previous pos&lt;/a&gt;t about parsing XML where I used the information from &lt;a class="link" href="https://voiceofthedba.wordpress.com/2015/01/26/downloading-sql-saturday-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Steve Jones blog post&lt;/a&gt; to get information from the &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.sqlsaturday.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;SQL Saturday web site&lt;/a&gt; I thought that this information and script may be useful for others performing the same task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit - This post was written prior to the updates to the SQL Saturday website over the weekend. When it can back up the script worked perfectly but the website is unavailable at the moment again so I will check and update as needed once it is back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SQL Saturday Exeter&amp;ndash;What&amp;rsquo;s the Point? My Experience of 2013 SQLSatExeter</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeterndashwhatrsquos-the-point-my-experience-of-2013-sqlsatexeter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeterndashwhatrsquos-the-point-my-experience-of-2013-sqlsatexeter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer – I am on the committee organising the next &lt;a class="link" href="http://sqlsouthwest.co.uk/sqlsat269/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;SQL Saturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt;. To be kept up to date about SQL Saturday #269 in the South West, follow &lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/sqlsatexeter" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;@SQLSatExeter&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23sqlsatexeter&amp;amp;src=hash&amp;amp;f=realtime" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;#SQLSatExeter&lt;/a&gt; on twitter and see details at the bottom. This post is about my experience at this years event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March this year the SQL South West User Group hosted SQL Saturday #194 in Exeter. I was a new member to the User Group having finally been able to join them for the first time in January. At that meeting Chris Testa O’Neill presented a session and was very passionate about the SQL Community and the benefit of the SQL Saturdays and other events.  I am always keen to learn new things and find ways of developing my skills. As I haven’t won the lottery I also look out for good deals as well!!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>