<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teams on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/teams/</link><description>Recent content in Teams on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/teams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notifying a Teams Channel of a SQL Agent Job result</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/notifying-a-teams-channel-of-a-sql-agent-job-result/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/notifying-a-teams-channel-of-a-sql-agent-job-result/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2020/07/image-18.png" alt="Featured image of post Notifying a Teams Channel of a SQL Agent Job result" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.robsewell.com/sending-a-sql-agent-job-results-overview-to-a-microsoft-teams-channel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;yesterdays post about creating an overview of SQL Agent Job Results and sending it to a Teams channel&lt;/a&gt;, I was given another challenge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you write a job step that I can add to SQL Agent jobs that can send the result of that job to a Teams Channel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person with a need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use case was for some migration projects that had steps that were scheduled via SQL Agent Jobs and instead of the DBA having to estimate when they would finish and keep checking so that they could let the next team know that it was time for their part to start, they wanted it to notify a Teams channel. This turned out especially useful as the job finished earlier than expected at 3am and the off-shore team could begin their work immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sending a SQL Agent Job results overview to a Microsoft Teams Channel</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/sending-a-sql-agent-job-results-overview-to-a-microsoft-teams-channel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/sending-a-sql-agent-job-results-overview-to-a-microsoft-teams-channel/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2020/07/image-11.png" alt="Featured image of post Sending a SQL Agent Job results overview to a Microsoft Teams Channel" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Teams is fantastic for collaboration. It enables groups of people, teams if you like to be able to communicate, collaborate on documents, hold meetings and much much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sql-agent-job-overview"&gt;SQL Agent Job Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a class="link" href="http://dbatools.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;dbatools&lt;/a&gt; we can create a simple script to gather the results of Agent Jobs form a list of instances. Maybe it would be good to be able to get the job runs results every 12 hours so that at 6am in the morning the early-bird DBA can quickly identify if there are any failures that need immediate action and at 6pm , the team can check that everything was ok before they clock off.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>