<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rationalise on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/rationalise/</link><description>Recent content in Rationalise on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/rationalise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove-SQLDatabaseSafely My First Contribution to DBATools</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/remove-sqldatabasesafely-my-first-contribution-to-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/remove-sqldatabasesafely-my-first-contribution-to-dbatools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What is DBA Tools?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collection of modules for SQL Server DBAs. It initially started out as ‘sqlmigration’, but has now grown into a collection of various commands that help automate DBA tasks and encourage best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about &lt;a class="link" href="https://dbatools.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and it is &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/ctrlbold/dbatools" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;freely available for download on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; I thoroughly recommend that [you watch this quick video]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PciYdDEBiDM"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to see just how easy it is to migrate an entire SQL instance in one command Longer session here&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rationalisation of Database with Powershell and T-SQL part two</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/rationalisation-of-database-with-powershell-and-t-sql-part-two/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/rationalisation-of-database-with-powershell-and-t-sql-part-two/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2014/03/030314_2100_rationalisa1.png" alt="Featured image of post Rationalisation of Database with Powershell and T-SQL part two" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.robsewell.com/rationalisation-of-database-with-powershell-and-t-sql-part-one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I showed the script to create an Excel Workbook, colour coded showing the last used date for all of the databases on servers in my sqlservers.txt file. After gathering that information over several months, there is then a requirement for someone to make a decision as to which databases can be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously there will be some databases that are read-only or if not set specifically as read-only may only be used for reference without data being added. You should hopefully have knowledge of these databases and be able to take them off the list quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rationalisation of Database with Powershell and T-SQL part one</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/rationalisation-of-database-with-powershell-and-t-sql-part-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/rationalisation-of-database-with-powershell-and-t-sql-part-one/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2014/02/usage-excel.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Rationalisation of Database with Powershell and T-SQL part one" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have recently been involved in a project to rationalise databases. It is easy in a large organisation for database numbers to rapidly increase and sometimes the DBA may not be aware of or be able to control the rise if they don’t have knowledge of all of the database servers on the estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of benefits of rationalisation to the business. Reduced cpu usage = reduced heat released = lower air-con bill for the server room and less storage used = quicker backups and less tapes used or better still less requirement for that expensive new SAN. You may be able to consolidate data and provide one version of the truth for the business as well. Removing servers can release licensing costs which could then be diverted elsewhere or pay for other improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>