<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ola Hallengren on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/ola-hallengren/</link><description>Recent content in Ola Hallengren on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/ola-hallengren/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PowerShell, Pester and Ola Hallengrens Maintenance Solution</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershell-pester-and-ola-hallengrens-maintenance-solution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/powershell-pester-and-ola-hallengrens-maintenance-solution/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2016/09/pester-ola-check.png" alt="Featured image of post PowerShell, Pester and Ola Hallengrens Maintenance Solution" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a SQL DBA you will have heard of &lt;a class="link" href="https://ola.hallengren.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ola Hallengrens Maintenance solution&lt;/a&gt; If you haven’t go and click the link and look at the easiest way to ensure that all of your essential database maintenance is performed. You can also &lt;a class="link" href="https://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event9/Inside_Ola_Hallengrens_Maintenance_Solution" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;watch a video from Ola at SQL Bits&lt;/a&gt;
Recently I was thinking about how I could validate that this solution was installed in the way that I wanted it to be so I turned to &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/pester/Pester" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Pester&lt;/a&gt; You can find a great &lt;a class="link" href="https://mcpmag.com/articles/2016/05/19/test-powershell-modules-with-pester.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;how to get started here&lt;/a&gt; which will show you how to get Pester and how to get started with TDD.
This isn’t TDD though this is Environment Validation and this is how I went about creating my test.
First I thought about what I would look for in SSMS when I had installed the maintenance solution and made a list of the things that I would check which looked something like this. This would be the checklist you would create (or have already created) for yourself or a junior following this install. This is how easy you can turn that checklist into a Pester Test and remove the human element and open your install for automated testing&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scheduling Ola Hallengrens Maintenance Solution Default Jobs with PowerShell</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/scheduling-ola-hallengrens-maintenance-solution-default-jobs-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/scheduling-ola-hallengrens-maintenance-solution-default-jobs-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a SQL Server DBA you should know about Ola Hallengren and will probably have investigated his Maintenance Solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t please start here &lt;a class="link" href="https://ola.hallengren.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://ola.hallengren.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also watch his presentation at SQLBits at this link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event9/Inside_Ola_Hallengrens_Maintenance_Solution" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;http://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event9/Inside_Ola_Hallengrens_Maintenance_Solution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where he talks about and demonstrates the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to just run his script to install the solution and schedule the jobs and know that you have made a good start in keeping your databases safe. You should be more proactive than that and set specific jobs for your own special requirements but you can and should find that information in other places including the FAQ on Ola&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>