<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Volunteering on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/volunteering/</link><description>Recent content in Volunteering on Rob Sewell (aka SQL DBA With A Beard)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.robsewell.com/tags/volunteering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Day In The Life of a SQLBits Volunteer</title><link>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-sqlbits-volunteer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.robsewell.com/blog/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-sqlbits-volunteer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2016/05/dscn0286-3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Day In The Life of a SQLBits Volunteer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2016/05/dscn0286-3.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.robsewell.com/assets/uploads/2016/05/dscn0286-3.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="image"
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So SQLBits has finished for another year. About 1500 people registered for the largest SQL Conference in Europe held over 4 days in Liverpool last week. 2 days of full day sessions and 2 days of shorter sessions, a pub quiz, a party (literally) out of this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is organised and run by volunteers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you’re right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we must pay special thanks to Simon, Darren, Chris, Jonathan, Annette, Allan and Alex without forgetting all that JRJ has done. They ensured that the venue, sessions, speakers, sponsors, audio visual and not forgetting the amazing party by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sneaky Experience (Thank you Julia),&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; all occurred at the right time in the right place with the right people and the work and effort they have put in cannot be over-estimated but this post isn’t about those generous, inspiring, amazing folk
Several people asked me what a volunteer does and how they can become one and hopefully this post will answer both of those questions. More than 40 people volunteered to help at SQL Bits&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>